# MBA Resume Guide & Tips



#### Alya Aminah

(1234) 451 451

MBA Candidate - Digital Marketing Professional

San Francisco, CA

Georgetown University MBA backed by multiple certifications (Google Analytics IQ, AdWords, SEO), as well as broad-based experience as a digital marketing director, media campaign manager, and volunteer within F500, startup and nonprofit settings. Demonstrated success delivering key consumer insights, digital innovation strategy and tactical campaign support to propel pacesetting gains to web traffic, customer acquisition and eCommerce revenues.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Digital Marketing Director

JLC Communications

alya@novoresume.com

11/2017 - 04/2020

San Francisco, CA

- Optimized AdWords campaigns, reducing wasted spend, expanding brand awareness, and improving conversion rate resulting in \$1.2MM in revenue.
- Oversaw various digital marketing channels, collaborating with Marketing and Design in conceptualizing marketing strategies with digital elements.
- Set in motion new technologies and digital elements, integrating them into marketing and sales campaigns for customer engagement.
- Administered innovative concepts on online to offline event & marketing plans, in coordination with clients' Marketing, Public Relations, and Operation teams.
- Designed and implemented social media digital strategies, in-store digital activations, providing data for customer behavior analysis.
- Build, plan, and implement the overall digital and social media marketing strategy, aligning content with short-term and long-term marketing goals.

#### Media Campaign Manager

Delphus Company

02/2014 - 10/2017

San Francisco, CA

- Successfully boosted social media followers by 80% via maximization of WeChat, Facebook, and other digital media, nurturing new online communities for the company.
- Improved SEO advantage and brand effectiveness via customized microsites for brands, resulting in a 50% revenue increase.

#### AREAS OF EXPERTISE

in linkedin.com/in/alya.aminah

CRM (Salesforce, SAP, GoldMine) Brand Awareness

Strategic Marketing Competitive Analysis

SEO/SEM Financial Forecasting HTML

Product Development Market Research & Analysis

Social Media Advertising Cocale Adwerds | Analysis

🥑 @alya.aminah

#### **COURSES & TRAINING**

Content Marketing, SEO and PPC (2019) SEMRUSH Academy

Inbound Marketing & Contextual Marketing (2018) HubSpot

Email Marketing & Sales Funnels (2018)

ClickMinded Digital Marketing

Google Digital Marketing Courses (2017)

Digital Garage

#### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

#### — Media Manager

2018 - Present

Meals on Wheels

San Francisco, CA

- Hold a volunteer position as a Media Manager, developing & implementing all targeted content for various media platforms.
- Research, author, proofread and edit all media content,

# How to Structure & Format It

We recommend the "reverse-chronological" format, which is the most common.

Follow these tips for a professional layout:

- Stick to one-inch margins on all sides.
- Pick a font that stands out, but not too much.
- Use a font size of 11-12pt for normal text and 14-16pt for headers.
- Use 1.0 or 1.15 line spacing.
- Don't go over the 1-page limit.

# Sections to Include

#### **Must-Have Sections**

- Contact Information
- Work Experience
- Skills
- Education
- Certificates



## **Optional Sections**

- Awards & Achievements
- Volunteer Experience
- Personal Projects
- Languages
- Interests & Hobbies

# Include a Resume Summary or Objective

## Resume Summary Example

"Professional Marketing Analyst with 5+ years of experience in creating ads, writing copy, and overseeing campaigns. Improved revenue by 34% for Company X in 2017. Looking to leverage my marketing expertise to contribute to School X's knowledge exchange."

## Resume Objective Example

"Enthusiastic Business Management graduate, with one year experience as a freelance marketing consultant. Created creative copy for Client X, which increased conversions by 65%. Skilled in SMM, SEO, copywriting, and web design. Seeking a chance to offer my unique insights on marketing, while developing my skills in management."

## **Use Action Verbs**

Use these power words to list your work responsibilities and achievements:

- Conceptualized
- Designed
- Devised
- Determined
- Drafted
- Formulated
- Introduced
- Initiated
- Launched
- Originated
- Spearheaded



# Top Skills to Mention

### **Hard Skills**

- Quantitative research
- Big data analysis
- Financial forecasting

### **Soft Skills**

- Communication
- Leadership
- Teamwork
- Strategic thinking
- Learning from criticism